Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection, 1931-1964
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- El Caiman; Los Arbolitos, Trio Calaveras, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana, SA. El Caiman -- Los Arbolitos (Chucho Martinez Gil) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.302 (10in.)
- La Calandria; Las Tres huastecas, Los Trovadores Plateados, April 7, 1921; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; [Mexico, D.F.], Peerless. Huapango: La Calandria (Nicandro Castillo) -- Las Tres huastecas (Nicandro Castillo) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.303 (10in.)
- El Barzon; La Mula bronca, Guerrero, Lalo and El Mariachi Imperial, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; El Barzon (Jose Rodriguez) -- La Mula bronca (Victor Cordero) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.304 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Nava, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; New York, Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. Corrido - Acomp. de guitarra (Jesus Leal) -- Corrido - Acomp. de guitarra (Heraclio Bernal) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.305 (10in.)
- Hay un lirio; Los Gavilanes, Trio Jaliciense, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Voralion. The Trio Jaliciense is a male trio, with violin, guitar, and clarinet... Hay un lirio (There is a lily, I.M. Valle) -- Pespunte: Los Gavilanes (The Sparrow-hawks, I.M. Valle)... Disc is broken...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.306 (10in.)
- Corrido de Jesus Garcia, Posada y Molina, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; New York, N.Y., Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. Corrido de Jesus Garcia (El Hero de Nacozari), Parts I and II (E. Perez) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.307 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 10 in.; Rigas. Titles and performers listed in Russian; SWF PRE1980.1/D.308 (10in.)
- El Celoso; Margarita, Trio Ramirez-Valles-Fierro and Orquesta Acosta, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; New York, N.Y., Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. El Celoso (Ed. Tavo) -- Margarita (Ed. Tavo) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.309 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Owen, Dock, Paine Denson, Lee Wells, and L.P. Odem, 1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratories. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and George Pullen Johnson of Birmingham, Alabama, August, 1942...Led by Dock Owen of Marshall County, Alabama: Windham -- Led by Paine Denson of Birmingham, Alabama: Mear -- Led by Lee Wells of Jasper, Alabama: Wondrous Love -- Led by L.P. Odem of St. Joseph, Tennessee: Lover of the Lord --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.238
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Posey, Mrs. Delilah Denson, Paine Denson, Mrs. Maude Moncrief, and Mrs. M.L. Mann, 1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratories. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and George Pullen Jackson of Birmingham, Alabama, August, 1942... Led by Mrs. Delilah Denson Posey of Birmingham, Alabama: Northfield... Led by Mrs. Maude Moncrief of Birmingham, Alabama: Mount Zion... Led by Mrs. M.L. Mann of Opelika, Alabama: Milford...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.239
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Posey, Mrs. Delilah Denson, John M. Dye, Euna Vee Denson Nail, and Ernestine Tipton, 1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratories. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and George Pullen Jackson of Birmingham, Alabama, August, 1942...Led by Ernestine Tipton of Birmingham, Alabama: Ballstown... Led by Mrs. Delilah Denson Posey of Birmingham, Alabama: Edom... Led by John M. Dye of Birmingham, Alabama: Stratfield... Led by Euna Vee Denson Nail of Birmingham, Alabama: Evening shade...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.240
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Tipton, Ernestine, Dock Owen and A. Marcus Cagle, 1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratories. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and George Pullen Jackson of Birmingham, Alabama, August, 1942... Led by Ernestine Tipton of Birmingham, Ala.: Fillmore... Led by Dock Owen of Sand Mountain, Marshall County, Ala.: Sardis... Led by A. Marcus Cagle of Atlanta, GA.: Mission -- Vain world adieu --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.241
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Denson, Paine, Howard Denson and R.M. Hornsby, 1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratories. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and George Pullen Jackson of Birmingham, Alabama, August, 1942... Led by Paine Denson of Birmingham, Ala.: Heavenly vision... Led by Howard Denson of Tuscaloosa, Ala.: David's lamentation... Led by R.M. Hornsby of Clay County, Ala.: Sherburne...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.242
- Edna Ritchie, Ritchie, Edna, 1962; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Huntington, VA., Folk Legacy Records, Inc. May day carol -- Gentle fair Jennie -- The riddle song -- Old Tyler -- Old Crumley -- Aunt Sal's song -- Foreign landes -- Dear companion -- Old King Cole -- Somebody's tall and handsome -- Down came an angel -- The Cuckoo -- Old chimney sweeper -- Fair and tender ladies -- Blackest crow -- I wonder when I shall be married -- An Old man came courting me -- Jackero -- As Joseph was a-walking --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.243
- Haul on the bowlin' and other shanties & foc'sle songs, Lloyd, A.L. Ewan MacColl and Harry Corbett, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Stinson Records. Haul on the bowlin'(A.L. Lloyd & chorus) -- Row bullies, row (Ewan MacColl) -- The coast of Peru (A.L. Lloyd) -- The black ball line (Ewan MacColl & chorus) -- The Ship in distress (A.L. Lloyd) -- The Ganger (Ewan MacColl) -- Blow the man down (Harry Corbett & chorus) -- Do me ama (A.L. Lloyd) -- Santy Anna (A.L. Lloyd and chorus) -- The Flying cloud (Ewan MacColl) -- A Hundred years ago (A.L. Lloyd & chorus) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.244
- Hawaiian chant, hula and music, Kiona, Kaulaheaonamiku, 1962; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, NY., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded in Hawaii by Jacob Feuerring with vocals by Kaulaheaonamiku Kiona accompanied by native instruments... Kauka Hali'a I ka -- Kahiki Lan Lani -- He Wahini Holo Lio -- Pihanakalani -- Heeia -- Hilo E -- Hela Mai A Kalani -- Au'a la E Kama Moku -- Hole Waimea -- Maika' I Kaua'I -- Kona Kai Opu -- Auhea Wale Ana 'Oe -- Kauliua I Ke Anu Waialeale -- Ohe Hano Ihu --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.245
- Marie Hare, 1962; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Huntington, VT., Folk-Legacy Records, Inc. Green Valley -- Patrick O'Donnell -- Green grows the laurel -- Maid of the east -- The Jam on Gerry's rocks -- The Banks of the Miramichi -- The Wexford lass -- Billy Grimes -- Jenny dear -- Peter Emberley -- Her mantle so green --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.246
- Mountain music bluegrass style, 1959; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, NY., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded and annotated by Mike Seeger... Katy Hill (Tex Logan) -- Short life of trouble (Earl Taylor & the Stoney Mtn. Boys) -- Katy Cline (Don Stover, Chubby Anthony, B. Lilly and E. Pegdon) -- The Philadelphia lawyer (Bob Baker and the Pike Country Boys) -- Natchez under the hill (Tex Logan) -- Ain't nobody gonna miss me (Lilly - Stover) -- Old Joe Clark (Mike Seeger - Bob Yellin) -- Little Willie (Bob Baker, etc.) -- Whitehouse blues (Earl Taylor, etc.) -- Nine pound hammer (Smiley Hobbs) -- Cricket on the hearth (Anthony - Stover) -- All the good times have passed & gone! (Earl Taylor, etc.) -- New River train (Anthony - Mike Seeger) -- Leather britches (Smiley Hobbs) -- Fox chase (Earl Taylor, etc.) -- Feast here tonight (Bob Baker) -- Bile em cabbage down (Stover, etc.) -- Rocky run (Jerry Stuart, Smiley Hobbs, and Pete Roberts) -- Snow dove (Bob Baker, etc.) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.247
- Duet songs of French Canada, Baillargeon, Helen and Alan Mills, 1955; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. J'entends le moulin -- Fringue, fringue! -- J'ai tant danse -- Aupres de ma blonde -- La Plume qui s'envle au vent -- Mon pere avait 500 moutons -- La-bas sur ces montegnes -- Le P'tit avocat -- C'est le bon vin qui danse -- Marie Madelaine -- Le Retour du marin -- Pambelibelo -- Voila la recompense -- C'est a boire -- Le Petit mousse -- I went to the market --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.248 (10in.)
- Creole songs of Louisiana, Van Wey, Adelaide and Robert N. Hill, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Remon -- Salangadon -- Lu-Lu-Lu -- Aine, De, Toue -- Paw' Piti' Mom'zelle Zizi -- Jacques, Jacques -- Compere lapin -- Papa va peche -- Tan' siro' E Dou' -- Maison Denise -- Street cries -- Hominy man -- Sand caller -- Pepper pot -- Rag man -- Horseradish seller -- Flower vendor -- Cantelope [vendor] -- Paralline seller -- Scissors grinder --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.249 (10in.)
- The Rambling Irishman, Brandon, Tom, 1962; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Huntington, VT., Folk-Legacy Records, Inc. The Rambling Irishman -- The Irish soldier boy -- There is a lady in this town -- Muskoka -- The Maid of the mountain brow -- The "Lady Leroy" -- The Flying cloud -- The Trans-Canada highway -- The Rock Island Line -- The Croppy boy -- Kevin Barry -- Patrick Sheehan -- The Blarney stone -- My bonny black Bess -- Jack Haggerty --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.250
- This Land is my land, Guthrie, Woody, Sam Eskin, Bill Banyon, Harry McClintock "Mac", Pete Seeger, Cisco Houston and Leadbelly, 1951; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; New York City, NY., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Sung by Woody Guthrie: This land is my land... Sung by Sam Eskin: Lumbermen's alphabet... Sung by Bill Banyon: Down the hatch... [Sung by] Harry McClintock "Mac": Jerry go and oil that car... Sung by Pete Seeger: Young man who wouldn't hoe corn... Sung by Woody Guthrie: Columbia River... Sung by Cisco Houston: Old blue -- Down in the mines -- Whoopee ti yi yo... Sung by Leadbelly: Old man -- Haul away Joe --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.251 (10in.)
- Pennsylvania Dutch Folk Singers, Britton, George, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 10 in.; New York, NY., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Hei lie, Hei Lo -- Lauterbach -- Alle Yahr En Kindlein -- Wie Kumm ich an des Grosswadder's haus -- Unser Saiwi -- Schloof bobbeli Schoof -- Joe Ratel -- Reide, Reide, geile -- Des bucklich mennli -- Eiei, rete, ridd'eoo -- in Einem Kiehlen grunde -- Schpinn, schpinn -- Siss net alli daag luschdich leewe -- Meedli, Widdu Heiere? --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.252 (10in.)
- Music of the Sioux and Navajo, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, NY., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Recorded by Willard Rhodes at Wanblee and Pine Ridge, SD., The Sioux: Rabbit dance -- Peyote cult dance -- Love song -- Sun dance -- Omaha dance -- Love song -- Honoring song... Recorded at Fort Wingate, NM., Pine Springs, Toadalena and Lukachukai, AZ., Mesa Verde National Park, CO., The Navajo: Riding song -- Song of happiness -- Spinning dance -- Spinning dance -- Corn grinding song -- Squaw dance -- Silversmith's song -- Night chant --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.254
- Music of the World's People, 1951; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, NY., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Edited by Henry Cowell... Russian Gypsy -- Bali -- Arabia -- Tahiti -- Tibet (Chant-lament for the dead) -- United States (Pretty Polly) -- Iceland (Song of greeting - Hlidarendakoti) -- Spain (Panteras) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.256
- Music of the world's peoples, vol. 2, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, NY., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Selected by Henry Cowell... Cuba (Sutileza) -- Finland (Velisurmaaja) -- Ukraine (There's a well in the field) -- Canada (Gaspian Bay): Adieu donc mes chers parents -- American Indians (Sioux): Courting melody -- Serbia (Ugasnule Oci Cerne) -- China (Hu-K'in melody) -- Italy (La novena dinatle) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.257
- Music of the world's peoples, vol. 2, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, NY., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Selected by Henry Cowell... Cuba (Sutileza) -- Finland (Velisurmaaja) -- Ukraine (There's a well in the field) -- Canada (Gaspian Bay): Adieu donc mes chers parents -- American Indians (Sioux): Courting melody -- Serbia (Ugasnule Oci Cerne) -- China (Hu-K'in melody) -- Italy (La novena dinatle) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.258
- Music of the world's peoples, vol. III, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, NY., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Compiled and edited by Dr. Henry Cowell... Mexico -- England (As I went out one May morning) -- Peru (Maraypatapi) -- Philippines ('Urukay chant) -- Philippines (Kalipay merrymaking) -- Puerto Rico (Baquine) -- Viet Nam (Instrumental) -- Bularia (Instrumental) -- Dahomey -- Washington Coast Indians (Bone game) -- Washington Coast Indians (Bone game) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.259
- Music of the world's peoples, vol. III, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, NY., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Compiled and edited by Dr. Henry Cowell... Argentina -- Hungarian gypsy (Instrumental) -- Trinidad (fire brigade) -- Zululand (Instrumental) -- Yugoslavia (Epic song) -- Brazil (Bambo Du Bambu) -- Thailand (Classical music drama) -- Turkey (Gazel Niguie Gultchini) -- Egypt (Ya Bougaitha Hatll Gaddarah) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.260
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interview, Baird, Amy Hancock, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in; University of Arizona Folklore Archive. Includes interview with Amy Hancock Baird, Safford, Arizona, on how she learned songs... Songs include: My sweet anoxa from Arizona -- Oh Rubin they tell me you are going away -- Where are you going, my pretty maid --; Frances Gillmor; SWF PRE1980.1/D.375
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Amy Hancock, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Amy Hancock Baird of Safford, Arizona sings: Young man who wouldn't hoe his corn -- Valley of Custer -- See a weary band of pilgrims -- O'er rugged hills and plains of sage -- Recorded by Frances Gillmor...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.379
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gardner, Gail, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; The Dude wrangler -- The Cowman's troubles -- Syerry Petes -- Moonshine steer --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.380
- Sea shanties, Borwn, Noble B. and Sailor Dad Hunt, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Recorded by the University of Wisconsin Recording Project and sung by Noble B. Borwn, Millsville, Wisconsin, 1946: A Yankee ship came down the river (Blow boys blow)... Recorded by Herbert Halpert and sung by Sailor Dad Hunt, Marion, Virginia, 1939: Blow the man down...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.381
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lewis, Phyllis and Margaret Eagle, 1946; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Wisconsin Dells, University of Wisconsin Recording Project. Buffalo song. Zuni. (Phyllis Lewis, age 10) -- Buffalo song with drum. Zuni. (Phyllis Lewis, age 10) -- Corn grinding song (Margaret Eagle, age ca. 40) Scraping of feet indicates the sound of grinding corn. This is one of the few work songs -- Navajo riding song (Margaret Eagle). Sung by the men as they ride ponies -- Navajo night chant #1 (Margaret Eagle playing drum and shaking rattle) -- Navajo night chant #2 (Margaret Eagle). Both men and women sing this song -- Navajo night chant #3 (Margaret Eagle) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.382
- Pre-1980 Interview, Jones, Alden, April 8, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Sells, AZ. Byrd Granger interviews Alden Jones et al. on Papago place names...Recording was made during a tribal council meeting in Sells, Arizona, April 8, 1956...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.385
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Narratives, Johnson, Molly, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; There was a man -- other unidentified songs... Johnson briefly discusses how she learned these songs...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.388
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections and Interviw, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Man sings with banjo accompaniment... Robin Hood and the peddler -- Interview -- Interview -- Sweet William and little Margaret -- I haven't a house in Baltimore -- Old Uncle Ned tune --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.389
- Pre-1980 Narratives, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Anonymous man, interviewed by anonymous woman, lectures and translates Navajo words into English...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.390
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 4 sound discs, analog, 12 in.; Soundcraft. Pre-1980-1/D.391-/D.406 are black, 12 inch discs...Each appears to have been cut, but no information is available on their contents...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.391 - /D.406
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A., May, 1948; : 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Mesa, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor for the University of Arizona Folklore Archive... Sung by Mrs. John A. Ray: Mein heart is broken all into little bits -- The Fallen leaf --; Frances Gillmor; SWF PRE1980.1/D.23
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Ray, Mrs. John A., May, 1948; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Mesa, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor... Sung by Mrs. John A. Ray: The Union soldier's grave -- They tell me the valley is smiling and fair -- The Toad said to the bumble bee --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.24
- Pre-1980 - Narratives, Anderson, M.F., Dr., 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Tucson, AZ. Dr. M.F. Anderson of Tuscon, AZ, recalls legends and stories... Spoken in Swedish...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.80
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; New York, N.Y., Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. Corrido: El Caballo Mojino (by A. Reza and Ed. Tavo; performed by Pena, Dominquez, Valles, Gomez, the Cancioneros "Acosta", the Orquesta Acosta) -- Cancion: Oye las suplicas (by Ed. Tavo; performed by Valles, Fierio, Gomex, the Cancioneros "Acosta", the Orquesta Acosta) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.310 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gonzalez, Pastor, y Cervantes, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Columbia Phonograph Company. La Pajarera (Gonzalez, Pastor y Cervantes) -- No llores (Pastor y Cervantes) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.311 (10in.)
- La Virgencita, [Parts I and II], Posada, L. and P.J. Gonzalez, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; New York, Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. La Virgencita, 1a parte (J. Peralta) -- La Virgencita, 2a parte (J. Peralta) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.312 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; New York, Okeh Phonograph Corporation. Recitations for Horacio C. Archilla: Palido, blanco y negro -- Adoracion --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.313 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gardel, Carlos, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Columbia [Phonograph Company, Inc.]. "Tomo y obligo" tango: Luces de Buenos Aires (Carlos Gardel and Manuel Romero) -- Tango: Como abrazado a un rencor (R. Rossi and Antonio M. Podesta) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.314 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Mariachi Tapatio, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana, S.A. Huapango: Cana de azucar (Lorenzo Barcelata) -- Cancion Ranchera: La Rosita (unknown)... Both songs are from the film, "Bajo el cielo de Mexico"...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.315 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Reyes, Lucha, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor. Disc is cracked and chipped... In Spanish... La Tequilera, by Alfredo D'Orsay (Lucha Reyes y Orquesta Armando Rosales) -- Traigo un amor, by E. Cortazar and M. Esperon (Lucha Reyes con el Mariachi Vargar de Tecalitla) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.316 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Guthrie, Woodie and Rebecca Tarwater, 1936; 1940; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded in Washington, D.C., 1940, by Alan Lomax and sung with guitar by Woodie Guthrie of Okemah, Oklahoma: The Gypsy Davy -- Recorded in Washington, D.C., 1936, by Charles Seeger and sung by Rebecca Tarwater of Rockwood, Tennessee: Barabara Allen --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.317 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lee, Buck, Jimmy Denoon and Booth Campbell, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; From paper insert: Recorded by Austin E. Fife and sung by Buck Lee, Clearfield, Utah, 1946: Billy Veniro, part 2. This is the second half of a poem by Eben Rexford in "Youth's Companion". Part 1 is on Pre-1980-1/D.356... Recorded by Vance Randolph and sung by Jimmy Denoon, Bradleyville, Missouri, 1942: Little old sod shanty... Sung by Booth Campbell, Cane Hill, Arkansas, 1942: Good old Rebel, or Unreconstructed Rebel. "Orginally a poem written by Innes Randolph, friend of Sidney Lanier, and has passed into folk tradition"...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.318
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Anderson, Mrs. Eugenia Blount, and Bascom Lamar Lunsford, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; From paper insert: Recorded by Duncan Emrich, Washington D.C., 1947, and sung by Mrs. Eugenia Blount Anderson, formerly of Macon Georgia, now of Baltimore, Maryland: Waillie, waillie or Cockle shells -- Careless love... Recorded by Artus M. Moser and sung by Bascom Lamar Lunsford at Swannanoa, North Carolina, 1946: Jesse James --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.319
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Mobeley, Pleaz, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; From paper insert: Recorded by Artus M. Moser, Etowah, North Carolina, 1946, and sung by [?]: I believe in the good old Bible... Recorded by Artus M. Moser, 1946, and sung by Pleaz Mobeley of Manchester, Kentucky: Wayfaring stranger... Recorded by Artus M. Moser, Renfro Valley, Kentucky, 1946, and sung by [?]: John Reilly... Recorded by Artus M. Moser, 1946, and sung by Pleaz Mobeley of Manchester, Kentucky: Darling Corey...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.320
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Eagle, Margaret, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; From paper insert: Performed by Margaret Eagle (age ca. 40): Zuni rain dance song. Opening song of the rain dance, "Maybe this year I will have a good crop; watermelons on this side, corn on this side. Look in the sky, - a cloud is appearing and will bring rain." -- Lullaby. Zuni. "Go to sleep my little baby while I work. Father will bring in the sheep soon." -- Zuni-Comanache song. Pleasure dance song. Has no words, only chanted syllables. -- Zuni-Comanche song. Pleasure dance song #2 --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.321
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Jones, Lewis w. and L.M. Hilton, 1946; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Recorded by Austin E. Fife, 1946... Sung by Lewis W. Jones of Monroe, Utah (age 77): Brighan, Brigham Young... Sung by L.M. Hilton of Ogden, Utah: Handcart song -- Pioneer Mormon --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.322
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Schaupp, Marianna and Mrs. May Kennedy McCord, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; From paper insert: Recorded by Alan Lomax, Washington D.C., 1941, and sung by Marianna Schaupp of Knoxville, Tennessee: Robin Hood and Little John... Recorded by Vance Randolph, 1941, and sung by Mrs. May Kennedy McCord, Springfield, Missouri: The Brown girl -- Lord Thomas and Fair Eleanor --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.323
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Grover, Mrs. Carrie, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; From paper insert: Recorded at Washington D.C., by Alan Lomax, 1941, and sung by Mrs. Carrie Grover of Gorham, Maine: The Loss of New Columbia, sea ballad from New England -- The Bay Biscay --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.324
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hermanos Huesca, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., Peerless. In Spanish... El Jarabe -- El Pajaro carpintero --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.325 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Tona la Negra [con] Orq. de Noe Fajaido, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., Peerless. In Spanish... El Apagon (Esperon - Cortazar) -- Que hombre tan simpatico (Esperon - Cortazar) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.326 (10in.)
- La Mariquita; El Zopilote Mojada, Mariachi Vargas de Tecalitlan, 1 sound disc, analog 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana, S.A. El Zopilote mojado -- La Mariquita --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.327 (10in.)